Guide to the Theater collection, 1844-1965
Department of Special Collections
Theater collection,
1844-1965
Special Collections M0154
.5 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Sources varied.
Scope and Content
Playscripts and letters (handwritten, typed, and some photocopies) from the nineteenth and twentieth centuries. Represented are playwrights, actors, and directors. Includes original material by Thomas W. Robertson and Joseph M. Field.
Access Terms
Barrett, Ed.; Cukor, George Dewey, 1899-; DeCroisset, Francis de, Madame.; Everpoint, 1810-1856.; Ferber, Edna, 1887-1968.; Gish, Lillian, 1896-; Head, Sydney W.; Jessel, George Albert, 1898-; Jordan, David Starr, 1851-1931.; Lawrence, Marjorie Kahl.; Lazarovich-Hrebelianovich, Princess.; Leblanc, Maurice, 1864-1941.; Lindsay, Howard, 1889-1968.; Macready, William Charles.; Manners, J. Hartley.; Nichols, Dudley, 1895-; Rathbone, Basil.; Robertson, T. W. (Thomas William), 1829-1871.; Terry, Ellen, Dame, 1848-1928.; Geary Theater (San Francisco, Calif.); Theater.; Scripts.
Container List
- Around the world in 80 days / by Jules Verne, Typescript of play. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Around the world in 80 days / by Jules Verne, Handwritten playscript, Act 3 missing. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Arranged exclusively for John Murray, Metropolitan Theatre. Dramatized by Frank G. Campbell, Sept. 28, 1879
- Arsene Lupin: play / by Francis DeCroisset & Maurice LeBlanc, Handwritten playscript in English. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Diamond Dick., Handwritten playscript. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Down in our village: original playscript / by Thomas W. Robertson, 1 bound v. + als (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Hearts and Diamonds / by Ed Barrett, Handwritten playscript. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Job and his children / by J.M. Field, copyist C.H. Morton. Property of W.H. Chippendale. Mobile Theatre, Jan. 1853, Original handwritten ms. (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Soldiers in the Dark / by Cpl. Sidney W. Head., Mimeograph playscript with ms. corrections & additions. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- The way: Christ and Evolution / by Princess Lazarovich-Hrebelianovich (nee Eleanor Calhoun).; forward by D.S. Jordan, Page or galley proofs of play. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Gift of David Starr Jordan.
- Early San Francisco Theater documents relating with the Geary Theater and the Pirates of Penzance. (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Cukor, George. TLS to Sam Stark, 1965 Apr. 20 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Ferber, Edna. TLS to Jerome Kern, 1933 June 2 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Purchase from Kaplan.
- Gish, Lillian. TLS to Mrs. Perara, 1950 Dec. 2 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Jessel, George. TLS to Sam Stark, 1961 Apr. 3 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Lawrence, Marjorie. TLS to Nathan Van Patten, 1950 Feb. 23 (Box 1, Folder 14a)
- Lindsay, Howard. TLS to Miss Perara, 1940 Nov. 22 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Macready, William Charles. ALS to Sir, 1844 Apr. 25 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Manners, J. Hartley. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - ALS to Queen of Roumania, 1922 Apr. 28
    Found in J. Hartley Manner's Peg O' My Heart PR4974.M15 918a.
  - Dedication to Queen of Roumania, n.d., ADS
  - Nibert. TLS to J. Hartley Manners, 1923 Mar. 21
- Nichols, Dudley. Xerox copy of TLS to Irving, n.d. Feb. 3 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Rathbone, Basil. ALS to Mrs. Perara, 1950 Oct. 28 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Terry, Ellen (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - ALS to Dear Old Nannie [i.e. Anna Held], 1889 Dec. 22
  - ALS to Dear Old Nannie [i.e. Anna Held], 1890 May 2
  - Terry, Minnie. ANS to John Jarvall with 2 tickets to the National Trust Ellen Terry Museum, 1962 July 18